创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
广袤太空中存在的物体和现象
In the vast reaches of space exist objects and phenomena...
其怪异程度是任何科幻小说家都想象不出的
as bizarre as any science fiction writer's imagination.
太空中有那么多的极端
There are so many extremes in space that it's really hard for a human being...
实在是让地球上的人类匪夷所思
here on planet Earth to imagine a lot of them.
想象一下粒子可以穿过你的身体
Picture a particle that can pass right through you...
一颗没听说过的行星正蛰伏在我们的太阳系里
a missing planet lurking in our own solar system...
星云里充满了我们所饮的酒精
and clouds filled with the alcohol we drink.
宇宙充满了各种稀奇古怪的东西
The universe is filled with all sorts of bizarre things...
不过通常的情况下 最怪异的现象
but it's often the case that the strangest phenomena...
最终会告诉我们宇宙之最
end up teaching us the most about the universe.
它们稀奇古怪 莫名其妙
They're outlandish, unexplainable...
匪夷所思
and unbelievably peculiar.
一起来光顾一下宇宙的怪异吧
Take a journey to the strange side of our universe.
宇宙:怪异之最
从我们的银河系
From our Milky Way galaxy...
一直到数十亿光年外遥远的地方
to remote regions billions of light-years away...
太空中充满了千奇百怪的东西
space is jam-packed with really weird stuff.
很难理解某些概念和我们在外太空里
It's hard to comprehend some of the concepts and things...
所发现的东西...
that we find in outer space...
因为它们根本不同于我们这星球的现实
because they're so profoundly different from life on our own planet.
我们认识越多 知晓越少
The more we learn, the less we know.
因此看来宇宙中有无穷无尽的怪异
So there's a seemingly limitless supply...
有待于发现
of strange things about the universe that remain to be discovered.
宇宙充满的各种对象
The universe is filled with objects...
和种种神秘的现象
and all sorts of mysterious phenomena...
是我们没有完全搞明白的
that we still don't fully understand.
似乎很怪异
Strange as it may seem...
天文学家发现星云里
astronomers have discovered interstellar clouds...
实际上充满了和啤酒里所能见到的一模一样的酒精
actually filled with the same kind of alcohol found in beer.
最奇怪的星云之一
One of the strangest clouds...
充满有机分子
is one that's filled with organic molecules...
尤其是乙醇
in particular, with ethyl alcohol.
那个 当然就是我们所喝的老酒
Now, that, of course, is the alcohol we drink.
所以这种巨大的宇宙酿酒厂的想法
And so the idea that there could be...
或许是一种可笑的想法
this huge cosmic distillery is kind of a fun idea...
但事实上 一点没错
but in fact, that's correct.
庞大的分子云是气体与尘埃的巨大的混合体
Giant molecular clouds are enormous complexes of gas and dust.
其中有些是我们太阳系大小的上千倍
Some of them are up to a thousand times the size of our own solar system.
其致密庞大的核心
Their dense and sizable cores...
足以形成复杂的分子
allow for the formation of complex molecules...
产出宇宙鸡尾酒
that can produce a cosmic cocktail.
在这个酿酒厂里
In this microbrewery...
大麦 水和酵母用于生产酒类
barley, water, and yeast are used to produce alcohol...
然而在星际分子云里
whereas in interstellar molecular clouds...
是尘埃颗粒团 在关键的成核点里
it's dust grains that serve as the key nucleation site...
将一些较简单的分子 如氢分子
for simpler molecules like molecular hydrogen...
水 二氧化碳聚集在一起 发生化学反应
water, and carbon dioxide to come together and react chemically...
形成较为复杂的分子 如乙醇
to form more complex molecules like ethyl alcohol.
随着尘埃颗粒团...
When the dust grains migrate...
迁移至分子云的中央
closer to the center of the molecular cloud...
它们就会接近正在中央逐步形成的中央星
they start to approach the central star that's forming in its core...
这会将它们加热
and this heats them up...
有可能足够蒸发掉某些复杂的分子
possibly enough to evaporate some of the complex molecules...
如乙醇蒸发进星际空间
like ethyl alcohol off and into interstellar space.
谢谢
Thank you.
请用
Cheers.
这个 如这个啤酒吧一样
So, just like this microbrewery...
星际分子云里的尘埃颗粒团
the dust grains in interstellar molecular clouds...
担当了孤单分子的碰头地点
serve as meeting places where lonely molecules...
以形成较为复杂的分子
can form more complex molecules.
首个酒精云是在1875年发现的
The first alcohol cloud was detected in 1975.
从此 更多的千奇百怪的星云
Since then, many more of these truly strange space clouds...
被发现了
have been observed.
星云G34.3 位于天鹰座里
The cloud G 34.3, which resides in the constellation Aquila...
其直径是我们太阳系的1000倍
is 1,000 times the diameter of our solar system.
事实上 G34.3里的乙醇足以
In fact, in G 34.3, there's enough ethyl alcohol...
每天供应30万品脱的啤酒
to supply 300,000 pints of beer every day...
给我们地球上每一个人
to every single person on planet Earth...
足以供应10亿年
for the next billion years.
那会是个万醉不休啊
That'd be one heck of a party.
唯一的不足
The only downside...
就是会让你闹头痛
is that it would probably give you a pretty bad headache...
因为它混有氰化氢
because it's also mixed in with hydrogen cyanide...
一氧化碳 二氧化碳 氨
carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide, ammonia...
以及其他一些不太好的化学物质
and some other fairly not-so-nice chemicals.
它们看似醉云摇摇晃晃飘荡在太空里
They may seem like inebriated clouds drifting aimlessly in space...
但是听来有点难以置信
yet as unbelievable as it may sound...
这些星云最终会形成多种多样的恒星系
these clouds eventually form multiple star systems...
行星
planets...
乃至生命
and maybe even life.
在星云的外缘
In the outer edges of the cloud...
这些冰冷的尘埃颗粒团携带着它们复杂的分子
these frozen dust grains with their complex molecules...
依旧完好如初
still remain intact.
事实上 我们知道它们今天成为了彗星
And, in fact, we know them today as comets...
被认为是这些彗星肩负着
and it's thought that these comets may be responsible...
将某些较为复杂的分子
for bringing some of these more complicated molecules...
带入太阳系内部
into the inner solar system.
事实上 它们有可能在我们的星球上播下了这些分子
In fact, they may have seeded our own planet with these molecules...
作为构建我们生命所需物质
which are the building blocks of things like amino acids...
如氨基酸的基石
which we need for life.
我们的太阳 地球脱胎于星云
Our Sun and Earth were formed out of an interstellar cloud...
诸如此类的星云
much like this cloud.
你只要有了合适的成分
And if you've got the right ingredients...
有合适的有机成分
the right organic ingredients...
你就有了合适的成分来构建生命
you've got the right ingredients for life.
貌似真的很怪异 会有这种巨大的酒精云
It may seem really weird that there's this giant cloud of alcohol...
漂浮在太空中
floating through space.
不过我热衷的一个情况是
But one of the things that l love...
普通的有机分子 酒精是其中之一
is how common organic molecules, alcohol being one of them...
怎么会遍及星系乃至宇宙的
is throughout the galaxy and the universe.
我们发现它们无处不在
We find them everywhere.
如果你将地球碾成粉末
If you pulverize the Earth into powder...
那基本上星云的化学物质
that's basically what an interstellar cloud is like...
完全类同于我们的成分
all the chemicals that make us up.
饱含酒精的星云可能帮助了
Alcohol-laden clouds may have helped...
播撒生命的种子在地球
to sow the seeds of life on Earth...
然而 与听上去一样不可思议 生命本身可能其实是存在于
yet, as incredible as it may sound, life itself may actually exist...
其它类型的怪异星云里
in other types of truly weird clouds.
金星 我们太阳的第二颗行星
Venus, the second planet from our Sun...
表面炙热如地狱
has a hot, hellish surface...
但是怪异的是 其云层
yet, strangely, its clouds...
接近30英里的高处
which hover at an altitude of around 30 miles...
具有的温度却有可能是生命适宜的
bear temperatures that may be habitable for life.
那里的温度相当于地球表面的温度
The temperatures are roughly the same as Earth's surface.
气压也相当于地球表面
The atmospheric pressure is about the same as Earth's surface.
因此你可能会说 如果生命可以存在于地球
So you might say, if life can exist here on Earth...
那么或许也可以存在于金星上类似的环境中
perhaps it can exist in similar conditions on Venus.
如果生命确实存在于金星的云层里
If life does exist in the clouds of Venus...
那么一开始又是如何到那里了呢?
how did it get there in the first place?
据认为金星的大气层
It's thought that the atmosphere of Venus...
是所谓的失控的温室效应的产物
is the product of what's called a runaway greenhouse effect...
那里二氧化碳的堆积
where the buildup of carbon dioxide...
导致了表面温度的上升
causes the temperature to rise at the surface...
其中 如果金星上存在有液态水的海洋的话
which, if there were any liquid oceans of water on Venus...
它们也会最终蒸发 逃逸进空中
they would have eventually boiled away and escaped into space.
于是它有可能移到了上部
Then it may have migrated up...
较为宜居的大气层里
to the upper, more hospitable layers of the atmosphere.
生命如我们所知离不开水
Life as we know it needs water.
金星的云层里含有水
The clouds of Venus contain water...
表现为浓硫酸形式
in the form of concentrated sulfuric acid.
在地球上 科学家发现了叫做嗜极菌的微生物
Here on Earth, scientists have found organisms called extremophiles...
茁壮成长在类似的酸性液体里
that thrive in similar acidic liquids...
如黄石国家公园的温泉里
such as the hot springs in Yellowstone National Park.
因此有人士猜测有机物
So some have speculated that organisms...
可以生存在金星的云层里
could survive in the clouds of Venus...
它们甚至已经进化到了
and they may have even evolved ways...
利用可利用的紫外线
of making use of available ultraviolet light...
宛如植物利用可见光一样进行光合作用
much like plants use visible light for photosynthesis.
你在云层里有大量的化学反应
You have a lot of chemistry going on in the clouds.
你有硫
You've got sulfurs...
有氢 有其他元素
and you've got hydrogen and other elements...
收留与维持生命的必需品
that are needed to harbor life and to sustain life...
在那个高度大量存在
and those are abundant at those altitudes.
因此并非不可思议 生命可以生存或存在于
So it's not inconceivable that life could survive or exist...
金星的云层里
in the cloud layers of Venus.
有个方法可以测试生命是否存在于金星的云层里
One method to test whether life could exist...
那就是研究地球上空的云层
in the clouds of Venus is to examine the clouds above Earth.
地球上的测量 举个例子
Measurements here on Earth, for example...
捕获云层里的粒子 在实验室里进行研究
capturing particles of cloud and examining them in the lab...
已经表明很小的微生物和细菌
have shown that very small organisms and bacteria...
实际上可以就生存在那种漂浮不定的大气里
can actually survive just sort of floating through the atmosphere...
扶摇直上 随风飘荡
being caught up on updrafts and just gusts of wind.
它们也许可以在大气层里...
And they can perhaps survive in the atmosphere...
存活好长时间
for long periods of time.
类推 同样的情形也有可能
As an analogy, the same type of behavior...
发生在金星上
might be occurring on Venus.
因此 如果金星的大气层里存在生命
So, if there were life in the Venusian atmosphere...
有可能就只是长期不停飞行的物种
it mightjust be kind of flitting along for long periods of time.
航天局可能有朝一日派出使团前往金星
NASA may one day send a mission to Venus...
去看看其云层里是否有生命
to find out if there's life in its clouds.
不过眼下 科学家非常热衷于
But right now, scientists are keenly interested...
了解是否有另一颗特殊的行星存在于
to learn whether another truly peculiar planet exists...
我们的太阳系里
in our solar system...
一颗尚未被发现的神秘行星
a mysterious planet that has yet to be discovered.
行星X是一颗假设有可能存在于海王星之外的行星
Planet X is a hypothetical planet that may exist beyond Neptune.
行星X可以说是对未知行星的通用名字
Planet X is sort of a generic designation...
它在外太阳系的某处
for an unknown planet that's somewhere in the outer solar system...
有待于发现
that remains to be discovered.
天文学家在观察柯伊伯带时 开始
Astronomers began to speculate there might be a missing planet...
怀疑有可能存在着一颗失踪的行星
when observing the Kuiper Belt...
那是海王星轨道之外的冰冷石块的储存地
a repository for icy rocks beyond the orbit of Neptune.
柯伊伯带外缘叫做柯伊伯悬崖
The outer edge of the Kuiper Belt is called the Kuiper Cliff...
因为太空石块的密度在这里陡然下降
because the density of space rocks drops off steeply here.
这可能是由于海王星的引力
This could be caused by Neptune's gravitational pull...
或者是一颗未知的行星
or perhaps by an unknown planet.
对柯伊伯带里天体的减少的一个假设
One hypothesis for the drop-off in Kuiper Belt objects...
就是我们看到约50到55个天文单位背后
that we see after about 50 or 55 astronomical units...
有一颗行星潜伏在某个地方
is that there is a planet lurking out there somewhere...
可能像是将它们集中到那个区域里
which could be sort of herding them inside of that region.
科学家几十年来一直迷惑于
Scientists have wondered for decades...
我们太阳系究竟居留了多少行星?
how many planets our solar system harbors?
是否真的存在行星X?
Is there really a Planet X?
本来 冥王星 在发现时
Originally, Pluto, when that was discovered...
是被指定为行星X的
was designated as Planet X.
最近 有其它的...
More recently, there have been discoveries...
柯伊伯带天体发现
of other Kuiper Belt objects...
比如像厄里斯和塞德娜
things like Eris and Sedna, for example...
都曾被冠以行星X的名头
that have been assigned the designation Planet X.
太阳系深处依然有...
There still remains to be the discovery of a very large object...
发现大天体的存在
in the deep solar system.
因此就产生了这种想法
So there's sort of still this idea...
行星X或神秘的隐匿行星
that a Planet X or a mysterious hidden planet...
就躲在太阳系的某个地方
is out in the solar system somewhere.
科学家可能不久就能解开
Scientists may soon solve the mystery...
所谓的柯伊伯悬崖之谜
of the so-called Kuiper Cliff.
如果行星X确实存在 这些宇宙侦探将会找到它的
lf a Planet X really exists, these cosmic sleuths will find it.
我们认为我们应该能了解到
We think that we should be able to learn...
不管是否很快就能确定存在这样一颗行星
whether or not there really is such a planet relatively soon...
新一代的大规模调查
with the new generation of large scale surveys...
都将发现那里存在的任何东西
that are going to detect anything out there.
行星X或许有可能存在
Planet X may or may not exist.
不过有其他行星
But there are other planets...
被发现在遥远的太空中
that have been observed far off in space...
已经超出了这个世界
that are truly out of this world.
我们太阳系包括了某些异乎寻常的行星
Our solar system contains some pretty unusual planets...
但是我们并不是独一无二的
but we're not alone.
先进的望远镜已经发现了近300颗行星
Sophisticated telescopes have now identified nearly 300 planets...
都位于我们太阳系以外
that are located well beyond our solar system.
它们被称为日外行星
They're known as exoplanets.
最奇特的日外行星是脉冲星行星
The most peculiar exoplanets are pulsar planets.
根本不同于围绕我们太阳那样的恒星
Unlike most that orbit a star like our Sun...
这些行星围绕的是快速旋转的中子星 叫做脉冲星
these planets orbit a fast-spinning neutron star called a pulsar...
它发出脉冲射电辐射 宛如灯塔
which emits a pulsing radio emission much like a lighthouse.
1990年代 科学家居然发现了
In the 1990s, scientists actually discovered...
一组三颗脉冲行星
a trio of pulsar planets about 900 light-years away...
在约900光年外的室女座内
located in the constellation Virgo.
要我说 它们有可能被载入
If I had my say, they'd probably go down...
宇宙间最怪异的行星
as the weirdest planets in the universe.
这些行星都非常靠近脉冲星
And these planets are all very close in to the pulsar.
现在 行星真是无处不在
Now, that's no place for a planet to exist.
谁都没料到会发现有行星围绕着这些东西
Nobody expected to find planets around these things...
因为脉冲星 或中子星
because a pulsar or a neutron star...
是超新星爆发的残骸
is the remnant of a supernova explosion.
恒星将自己扯得粉碎
The star has ripped itself apart...
是宇宙间已知最暴戾 最无序的爆发
in one of the most violent, chaotic explosions known in the universe.
那么行星在那里干嘛?
So what are planets doing there?
这真是个意外
This was a real surprise.
这里有三颗行星
There are three of these planets...
其中两颗约是地球质量的4倍
and two of them are about four times the mass of the Earth...
第三颗行星约是月球质量的两倍
and the third planet is about twice the mass of Earth's Moon.
因此的确是很小的行星
So very small planets indeed.
事实上 它们的轨道基本上非常靠近它们的中子星
In fact, they orbit so close to their neutron star primary...
实际上也就在水星的轨道内
that they could actually fit within the orbit of Mercury.
因此它们非常接近
So they're very close in.
悬而未决的问题是这些行星是如何
The enduring question is how these planets...
躲过超新星事件劫难的
survived the supernova event at all.
要是同样的事情发生在我们的太阳
If the same thing happened to our Sun...
太阳系内部的行星早已经蒸发殆尽了
the planets in the inner solar system would've been vaporized.
如果我们所见到的那些行星在超新星爆发时
If those planets that we see were there at the time of the supernova...
躲过了一劫
and they survived it...
它们肯定会铲除有可能存在于
they certainly would extinguish any life...
那些行星上的任何生命
that might have been on those planets.
毫无任何生机
There's no hope for that.
光是威力和能量
Just the power and the energy...
以及超新星的辐射环境
and the radiation environment of the supernova...
都足以消灭任何东西
would make it pretty lethal to anything.
如果这三颗行星在超新星爆发时不是围绕着该星
If the three planets weren't orbiting the star...
那么它们又是如何在那个地方的呢?
at the time of the supernova explosion, then how did they get there?
也许这些怪异的脉冲星行星脱胎于
Maybe these weird pulsar planets formed...
超新星 那颗爆发恒星周围的残渣
from the debris surrounding the supernova, the exploding star.
也许有一个物质盘喷出
Maybe there was a disk of material...
但是它并没有完全消失
that was shot out, but it didn't quite escape...
留下了残渣盘 于是行星得以形成
and it left a disk of debris from which planets then formed.
我们真的不知道这些怪异的脉冲星行星是如何形成的
We don't really know how these weird pulsar planets form.
它们挑战着迄今以来所有的理论
They challenge all theories so far.
脉冲星行星将惊人的新见解推向了
Pulsar planets shed startling new insight...
整个宇宙里的太阳系的形成
into the formation of solar systems throughout the universe.
如果脉冲星行星形成在超新星爆发之后
If the pulsar planets formed after the supernova explosion...
那么其意义重大 因为它们表明
then they're important because they indicate...
行星的形成可以发生在相当极端
that planet formation can happen...
意想不到的环境中
in rather extreme, unexpected environments.
也许你不需要某些秩序井然的东西
Maybe you don't need something quite as orderly...
如形成我们太阳系的气体
as the gas that formed our own planetary system.
所以那真的是很酷
So that's really cool.
但是如果行星在爆发前就在那里了
But if the planets were there before the explosion...
并且依然受到该星的约束
and remained bound to the star...
那同样是对理论的有趣挑战
that's an interesting challenge to theory as well...
因为它表明不管怎样
because it shows that somehow...
行星在某种情况下可以依然受到约束
planets can remain bound in some cases.
脉冲星行星是怪物
Pulsar planets are oddities...
但是它们所围绕的中子星或脉冲星也相当怪异
but the neutron or pulsar stars they orbit are also quite bizarre.
中子星的物质密度极其大
Neutron star material is incredibly dense.
单位体积的质量极高
It has a very high mass per unit volume.
事实上 其密度相当于原子核
In fact, it's as dense as an atomic nucleus.
因此如果我铲上一铲沙子
So if l had a shovelful of sand...
这要是中子星的物质
and this were actually neutron star material...
其重量差不多如
it would weigh as much as Mount Whitney...
加州内华达山脉的惠特尼山
in the Sierra Nevada range in California.
其质量犹如大山
It would have as much mass as a mountain.
一桶这种中子星的物质
And a bucketful of this neutron star material...
重量差不多如地球上最大的高山
would weigh as much as Mount Everest...
珠穆朗玛峰
the biggest mountain on Earth.
现在 我可以轻而易举提起这桶沙子
Now, l can lift a bucket of sand quite easily...
但这要是中子星物质的话
but if this were actually neutron star material...
我是绝不可能提起珠峰的
there's no way I could lift Mount Everest.
这表明中子星物质的密度之大有多惊人
That shows how incredibly dense neutron star material really is.
有两种类型的中子星:
There are two types of neutron stars:
快速旋转并发出射电脉冲的中子星
pulsars that spin rapidly and emit beeping radio pulses...
以及旋转缓慢并发出磁能的磁星
and magnetars that spin slower and emit energy from magnetism.
磁星 比脉冲星罕见得多
Magnetars, which are much rarer than pulsars...
具有宇宙间最强的磁场
have the strongest magnetic fields known in the universe.
地球上没有任何地方 你可以看到有磁场
There aren't any places on Earth where you can find magnetic fields...
强大到你在磁星上所看到的那样
as strong as you find them in a magnetar.
不过好像这个特斯拉线圈可以与之匹敌
But there's kind of a parallel with this Tesla coil.
特斯拉线圈的最初实验者是尼古拉.特斯拉
The Tesla coil is originally experimented with by Nikola Tesla...
他试图解决
who was trying to figure out...
如何不用电线为家庭供电
how to provide electricity without having to wire homes...
而实际上是通过空中来供电
but actually provide electricity through the air.
特斯拉线圈有一个巨大的电压差
The Tesla coil has a big voltage difference.
中间的球与周围的笼子之间
About half a million volts between the ball in the middle...
有约50万伏的电压
and the cage that surrounds it...
那个压差就是能量的释放
and that gap is a release of energy...
也就是 电子在空中划过
that, when the electrons fly through the air...
释放出巨大的能量
it releases a tremendous amount of energy...
你就看到了那些火花
that you see in those sparks.
磁星的情况大同小异
A magnetar is kind of the same thing.
它是一种能量的释放
It's a release of energy...
你可以看到伽玛射线和X射线
that you see in gamma rays and X-rays.
磁星可以释放出巨大的能量爆发
Magnetars can release gigantic bursts of energy...
并不是中子星那样的有规律性 而是相当的随意
not in the periodic way like a pulsar, but rather sort of at random.
发生于外壳的情况 如星震
Something happens to the crust like a star quake...
与磁场的约束结合在一起
and a bunch of magnetic fields come together...
释放出的巨大能量
and release a tremendous amount of energy...
会转变成X射线和伽玛射线
which gets turned into X-rays and gamma rays.
磁星与脉冲星都是奇异之星
Magnetars and pulsars are both strange stars...
但是科学家发现了某些更为离奇的东西:
but scientists have discovered something even more bizarre:
有星体的行为如脉冲星和磁星一样
a star that acts like a pulsar and a magnetar.
航天局的罗西X射线计时探测器 观察到这颗异乎寻常的星体
NASA's Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer has observed this unusual star...
以耀斑形式喷发出五个巨大的能量爆发
ejecting five colossal outbursts of energy in the form of flares...
那是磁星的特征
which are characteristic of magnetars.
它们在2005年5 6月间共发生了5次
They occurred five times between May and July of 2005.
每一个耀斑持续不到一秒钟
Each flare lasted less than a second...
但是释放的能量相当于数万个太阳
but released energy equivalent to tens of thousand of suns.
作为一例脉冲星
There's been one case of a pulsar...
在经历了数次磁星般爆发后
which went through several magnetar-like outbursts...
那需要有非常强的磁场
that require this much stronger magnetic field...
某种磁场的重组
and some sort of a restructuring of the magnetic field...
突然释放出的能量大大超过了
that suddenly releases a lot more energy...
普通的脉冲星
than a normal pulsar.
我们至少有了一例脉冲星与磁星之间的
So we have at least one case of a link, or a missing link...
环节 或缺失的环节
between pulsars and magnetars...
脉冲星后来表现出某种磁星的现象
a pulsar that later showed some magnetar phenomena.
脉冲星 磁星组合星相当年轻
The pulsar-magnetar combo star is fairly young...
尚不足900岁
less than 900 years old.
因此天文学家认为中子星
So astronomers think neutron stars...
有可能以磁星开始自己的人生
may begin their lives as magnetars...
然后安顿下来变成了脉冲星
then settle down and become pulsars.
有可能许多中子星
It could be that many neutron stars...
最终变成了普通的脉冲星
that eventually become normal pulsars...
其实在经历磁星式爆发时
actually go through magnetar-like outbursts...
它们都很年轻
when they're very young...
也就几百岁或上千岁
just a few hundred years old or a thousand years old.
那可能是关键的环节
That could be the critical link.
我们看到的这个要比我们所看到的
We're seeing this one when it's much younger...
多数脉冲星年轻得多
than most pulsars that we see.
宇宙间有某些不同寻常的星球
Some unusual stars exist in the cosmos...
但太空中也同样有怪异的小不点存在
but there is equally odd small stuff in space.
最近 科学家已经解开了整个宇宙间
And recently, scientists have solved the mystery...
最难以捉摸的东西之一的谜团
surrounding one of the most elusive things in the entire universe...
每时每刻都在穿越我们的幽灵粒子
a ghostly particle that passes through us every second of every day.
宇宙号称拥有无穷无尽的...
The universe lays claim to infinite numbers...
异常行星和恒星
of abnormal planets and stars.
与此同时
At the same time...
太空中同样拥有怪异的小不点
there are equally strange small things in space.
人类以及大部分宇宙
Human beings and most of the universe...
是由普通物质构成的
are made up of normal matter...
其中主要包括了四种基本粒子
which primarily consists of four fundamental particles.
其中之一就是幽灵般的粒子 叫做中微子
One is a ghost-like particle called a neutrino.
中微子 我会认为是...
Neutrinos would be my vote...
宇宙间最奇异的普通物质
for some of the weirdest normal matter in the universe.
就在此时 每秒钟
At this very moment, every second...
有50万亿个中微子来自太阳
there are 50 trillion neutrinos actually coming from the Sun...
穿过我的身体
that are passing through my body...
还有中微子来自其它恒星
and there are other neutrinos from other stars...
从四面八方奔向地球
coming in different directions right through the Earth.
这些东西 数以万亿计 一刻不停涌入我体内
These things, by the trillions, are pouring into me every second...
但是我们却毫无觉察
but we're completely unaware of them.
它们根本不会与我们相互作用
They don't really interact with us at all.
有一种小粒子叫做中微子
There's a funny little particle called a neutrino...
是意大利语中的"小中性粒子"
Italian for "little neutral one."
它具有极小的质量 极少量的物质
It has very little mass, a very small amount of matter...
几乎没有 但它却具有能量
almost nothing, but it has energy...
它穿越空间 速度几近光速
and it zips through space at close to the speed of light.
这些东西是非互动性的
These things are so non-interactive...
要是你设想有一光年厚的铅
that if you imagine a light-year thickness of lead...
你拿一束中微子射向它
and you shined a beam of neutrinos toward it...
其中一半的中微子
half of those neutrinos...
将会穿过这一光年厚的铅
would make it through that light-year thickness of lead...
居然毫发无伤
completely unscathed.
中微子最常见是形成于
Neutrinos are most commonly formed...
恒星内部的核反应 包括我们的太阳
by nuclear reactions inside stars, including our Sun.
每秒钟约有600亿个太阳中微子
About 60 billion solar neutrinos...
穿过我们的拇指
pass through our thumbnails every second.
不过还有其它源头产生着中微子
But there are other sources that create neutrinos.
它们产生于核反应堆
They are produced by nuclear reactors...
有些产生于一直就在我们周围的岩石里的
there are some being produced by the radioactive decay...
元素的放射性衰变
of elements in the rock around us all the time.
还有实际上是产生于
And there are others that are actually produced...
宇宙射线轰击我们的大气层
when cosmic rays slam into our atmosphere.
它们轰击大气层的力量
And they hit the atmosphere literally with the force...
相当于时速100英里的快球
of a 100-mile-an-hour fastball.
海量的中微子被释放进宇宙
Vast numbers of neutrinos were released into the universe...
紧接着大爆炸 伴随着其它粒子和光
immediately after the Big Bang, along with other particles and light.
人类就是这种原生汤的后裔
Humans are the descendants of this primordial soup.
中微子是不同寻常的小不点
Neutrinos are unusual small objects...
但是同样存在着不同凡响的大玩意
but there are equally out of the ordinary big things.
小行星就是太阳系形成时
Asteroids are the rocky leftovers...
所残留的石头
from the formation of the solar system.
这些太空石块主要呆在
These space rocks primarily orbit...
火星与木星之间的小行星带里
within the asteroid belt between Jupiter and Mars.
在定居小行星带里的数十亿个里头
Among the billions that inhabit the asteroid belt...
有一个小行星真是模样古怪
there's one asteroid that's truly eccentric.
最怪异的小行星叫做图塔蒂斯
One of the strangest asteroids is one called Toutatis...
我想它之所以引人瞩目就在于它与众不同
and l guess it catches our attention a lot because it's odd.
它不是球形的
It's not perfectly round.
它有点畸形
It's kind of misshapen.
它看上去像是保龄球瓶 细长的
It sort of looks like a bowling pin, elongated...
下面鼓起来 然后有个狭长的脖子
like a bulge down here and then a narrow neck...
然后一头又鼓起来
and then another bulge.
有人甚至称
Some have even said...
它有可能是两个单独的物体松散地结合在一起的
it's maybe two separate objects loosely connected.
它有一个奇怪的自转周期 好像在翻跟斗
It's got a strange rotational period where it's sort of tumbling...
就像是没投好的橄榄球
kind of like a badly thrown football.
其旋转并没有任何主轴
It's not spinning along any of its primary axes.
它实际上是沿着三个方向
It's actually sort of spinning along all three...
在太空中翻滚
tumbling through space.
图塔蒂斯也有一个大椭圆轨道
Toutatis also has a highly elliptical orbit...
把它从小行星带里带到地球的轨道内
which carries it from the asteroid belt to inside the Earth's orbit.
它是颗越地小行星
It's an Earth-Crossing asteroid...
使它进入危险区
and that puts it in the danger zone...
成为潜在袭击我们的对象
as something that could potentially strike us.
2004年9月 图塔蒂斯近在咫尺
In September of 2004, Toutatis got too close for comfort.
该小行星不足百万英里
The asteroid came within a million miles...
即约我们月球距离的四倍
or about four times the distance to our Moon.
那是非常近的小行星
And that's really close for an asteroid...
尤其是对这么大的东西
especially for one that big...
如果它一头撞向地球
and if it were to crash into Earth...
是不会被我们的大气层减缓速度的
it would not slow down one bit by our atmosphere.
它确实会打击我们 对地球极具威胁
It would really smack us and be very devastating to Earth.
下一次接近过程要到26世纪
The next near passage isn't until about the 26th century...
数百年后了
so hundreds of years away.
所以我们和图塔蒂斯相安无事 但我们必须时刻关注
So we're in good shape with Toutatis, but we have to keep an eye on it.
图塔蒂斯是颗不规则的小行星
Toutatis is an irregular asteroid...
但是有许多更大 更怪异的宇宙天体
but there are much bigger and stranger cosmic bodies...
游荡在宇宙间
that roam the universe.
月球 也就是众所周知的卫星
A moon, also known as a satellite...
是天体 围绕着行星或较小的物体
is a celestial body that orbits a planet or a smaller object...
诸如矮行星或小行星
such as a dwarf planet or asteroid.
光我们太阳系里就有240个卫星存在
About 240 moons exist in our solar system alone.
可是地球的月球是太阳系里唯一的卫星
And yet Earth's Moon is the only satellite in the solar system...
可以完全遮挡太阳
that perfectly eclipses the Sun.
不过最奇怪的卫星之一
But one of the most curious moons...
属于我们外太阳系里的一颗巨大的气体行星
belongs to a gas giant planet in our outer solar system.
米兰达(天卫五)天王星的卫星之一 是在是一颗奇怪的卫星
Miranda, one of Uranus' moons, is really a weird moon.
它非常小
It's very small.
只有290英里宽
Its only about 290 miles across...
所以它刚好可以塞进
so it would tuck neatly...
纽约到华盛顿之间
in the sort of New York to Washington corridor.
但是它是一派混乱
But it is completely, you know, a mess.
米兰达被命名为...
Miranda has been named...
我们太阳系里的怪物卫星
the Frankenstein moon of our solar system...
因为其乱七八糟的表面
because of its haphazard surface.
其表面有各种地貌 峡谷
The surface has all kinds of features and canyons...
河流 裂缝 看上去就像
and flows and cracks, and it looks like...
刚被绞拧过 要知道
it's just been through the wringer, you know...
它经历过什么
that it's been through something.
尽管它只有290英里宽
Even though it's only 290 miles across...
它的峡谷却有12英里深
it has canyons that are 12 miles deep.
要知道 相比之下
You know, by comparison...
大峡谷长约280英里
the Grand Canyon is about 280 miles long...
深1英里不等
and is a mile deep or thereabouts.
使米兰达成为太阳系里最怪异的卫星之一
What makes Miranda one of the strangest moons...
就是它看上去好像是
in the solar system is that it looks as though it were--
它是其它卫星或行星的...
It was assembled from the leftover bits...
边角料做成的
of other moons and planets.
其表面有着两重性
It's got a dual nature about the surface.
你可以看到有些地区非常平坦
You've got certain regions that appear very flat...
而其他地区就变幻莫测了
and then other locations that are very dynamic.
米兰达困惑着天文学家
Miranda puzzles astronomers...
因为他们不清楚它究竟是怎么形成的
because they don't know exactly how it was formed.
一种理论认为在几十亿年前
One theory suggests that billions of years ago...
这颗小卫星牵涉到了一次宇宙冲击
the tiny moon may have been involved in a cosmic impact...
其威力之大 将它破碎成了许多冰块和石块
so immense that it broke into many icy and rocky pieces.
这些碎片会重新融合在一起
These pieces could have melded back together...
成为明暗相间图案和形状的大杂烩
in a hodgepodge of light and dark patterns and shapes.
不过另一种假设认为
But an alternative hypothesis suggests...
米兰达的地表是断裂的结果
that Miranda's surface is the result of faulting...
当时有巨大的压力形成
when enormous stresses build...
推动巨大的岩石超过了它们的极限
and push large rock masses beyond their limit.
很像地球上所发生的情况
It's much like what has happened here on Earth.
这里是南加州的华斯克巨岩
Vasquez Rocks here in Southern California...
我们看到的是地球表面
what we see is the result of two plates on Earth's surface...
两个板块彼此对撞的结果
that are sort of pushing against each other...
传递着巨大的压力
imparting a large amount of stress.
为了减轻压力
In order to relieve that stress...
你要产生皱褶 隆起地表
you're generating folding and buckling of the surface...
给我们带来这些引人注目的山尖
and that gives us these dramatic spires...
我们周围的这些
that we see all around.
类似的活动也发生在米兰达上
A similar type of action is occurring on Miranda...
在那里你看到其表面有巨大的压力
where you have enormous amounts of stress on the surface...
造成米兰达地表的皱褶和隆起
that are causing buckling and folding of the Mirandan surface...
产生了我们所见到的山峰和陡坡
generating the peaks and scarps that we see there.
米兰达只是构成我们银河系的
Miranda is just one of millions of unexplainable objects...
数百万个无法解释的天体之一
that make up our Milky Way galaxy.
但是我们的星系并非宇宙间最怪异的星系
Yet our galaxy isn't the strangest one in the universe.
有其它星系赋予了"怪异"一词以新的意思
There are others that give new meaning to the word "strange."
星系 是星际社区
Galaxies-- they're celestial neighborhoods...
由行星 恒星 气体 尘埃组成
made up of planets, stars, gas, and dust.
至少有1000亿个星系存在于可观察到的宇宙里
At least 100 billion of them exist in the observable universe...
但是很多天文学家认为最怪异的星系
but many astronomers think the most bizarre galaxies...
是极亮红外星系 即ULIRGs
are ultraluminous infrared galaxies, also known ULIRGs.
以红外线观察它们
When looking at them in the infrared light...
其亮度是普通星系的100倍
they are 100 times brighter than normal galaxies...
因此它们是宇宙间最明亮的
so they are among the most luminous in the universe.
这些极亮红外星系
The enormous amounts of energy being put out...
释放出的巨大能量
by these ultraluminous infrared galaxies...
是恒星形成时巨大爆发的结果
are the result of huge bursts of star formation.
在我们星系里 每年都会诞生一颗我们太阳大小的新星
In our galaxy, about one new star the size of our Sun is born every year...
但是在ULIRGs里 每年都会形成100颗新星
but in ULIRGs, about a hundred new stars are formed yearly.
恒星诞生于星际气体中
Stars are formed out of interstellar gas...
它们四周笼罩着尘埃
and they're surrounded by dust...
你是无法看到恒星的形成的
and you can't really see the stars forming.
但是那能量整个加热了尘埃
But all of that energy heats up the dust...
转而 发出了红外线
which, in turn, glows in infrared light.
所以你看到的这世世代代恒星发出的所有能量
So you're seeing all of the energy of all of these generations of stars...
被这些星系里的尘埃吸收
being absorbed and re-radiated in infrared...
并重新发出红外辐射
from the dust in these galaxies.
所以就像是裹尸布包裹着星系
So it's like there's a shroud over the galaxies...
不过裹尸布本身的发光极其明亮
but the shroud itself is glowing really, really brightly.
ULIRGs首次发现是在1980年代初
ULIRGs were first discovered in the early 1980s...
当时的红外天文卫星(IRAS)
when the infrared astronomical satellite known as IRAS...
偶尔发现有星系的红外波极其明亮
picked up galaxies that are extremely bright at infrared wavelengths...
其强度超过了我们的太阳有万亿倍
a trillion times more powerful than our Sun.
已发现的最亮的ULIRGs之一是f15307+3252
One of the most luminous ULIRGs has been identified as f15307+3252.
它位于70亿光年外的...
It's located seven billion light-years away...
牧夫座里
in the constellation Bootes.
那个名字中的数字指的是星座在空中的方向
The numbers in those names refer to the direction...
这样你就可以找到该天体了
the coordinates in the sky where you can find the object.
这星系非常明亮
This one is very bright...
相对来说 非常遥远
very, relatively speaking, distant...
是个激动人心的发现
and is a very exciting find...
因为居然有这么多的恒星在形成
because there's just so much star formation going on...
我们想弄个明白 为何会是那种情形?
and we want to understand, why is that the case?
它是如何发生的?
How did it happen?
究竟是什么导致了我们所见到的 这种大量恒星的形成的呢?
What triggered this enormous amount of star formation that we're seeing?
有一种假设认为这些星系非常活跃
One hypothesis has been that these galaxies are very active...
因为它们是与其它星系
because they're the product of either mergers...
兼并或失之交臂的结果
or near misses with other galaxies.
当一个星系与另一个星系遭遇或撞击在一起
When one galaxy passes close by another or actually hits it...
你可以看到大量气体的压缩
you can have compression of a large amount of gas...
可以掀起恒星形成的巨浪
which can set off huge waves of star formation...
或可以极其有效地将气体吸入中央的黑洞
or can very efficiently funnel gas into the central black hole...
产生大量的热量
causing a lot of heat to be produced...
延伸到周围的吸积盘里
in the surrounding accretion disk.
不过这依然是目前一个活跃的研究领域
But this is still an active area of research right now...
要真正搞清楚这个过程为何会
as to exactly why this process happens...
发生在产生这些不寻常的星系身上
to make these unusual galaxies.
极亮红外星系中心已经发现有...
Supermassive black holes have been detected...
超大质量黑洞
in the centers of ultraluminous infrared galaxies.
它们所在空域引力极其强大
They're regions of space where gravity is so strong...
任何东西都难逃其魔爪 甚至是光
that nothing can escape it, not even light.
然而 有一种更为怪异的黑洞
But there's an even stranger breed of black holes...
有可能也存在着
that may also exist.
迷你黑洞是一种假设的物体
Miniature black holes are hypothetical objects...
比原子核还小
smaller than atomic nuclei.
不同于它们的恒星质量或超大质量黑洞表哥
Unlike their stellar mass and supermassive black hole cousins...
迷你黑洞从来没有被发现过
mini black holes have never been observed...
但是许多科学家相信它们确实存在
but many scientists believe that they do exist.
迷你黑洞很可能并不稀罕
Mini black holes are probably nothing unusual.
很可能现在就有一个在我鼻子跟前
There's probably one right here in front of my nose right now...
这里有一个 那里有一个
and one here and one here.
我们或许被它们团团包围
We're probably surrounded by them.
迷你黑洞可能是大爆炸的...
Mini black holes might be primordial leftovers...
残羹剩菜
from the Big Bang.
爆炸有可能将物质的浓度
The explosion could have squeezed...
压缩到形成的黑洞...
concentrations of matter to form black holes...
小得要靠显微镜才能看到
too small to be seen with a microscope.
黑洞愈小 物质的丧失愈快
And the smaller the black hole, the faster it loses mass.
因此如果你有一个小小的黑洞 如山体那么大
So if you had a little, tiny black hole, like the mass of a mountain...
是在大爆炸不久诞生的
that was created shortly after the Big Bang...
那么到了现在 140亿年后
then right about now, 14 billion years later...
它就会蒸发很多
it will have evaporated so much...
其余的物质将会消失在巨大的爆炸中
that the remaining stuff will evaporate...
砰的一下子!
in a colossal explosion. Just, bam!
科学家可以证明迷你黑洞的存在
Scientist may prove mini black holes exist...
通过在地球上暂时制造出它们
by manufacturing them temporarily here on Earth.
在瑞士 科学家已经建造了大型强子对撞机
In Switzerland, scientists have built the Large Hadron Collider.
它是一个粒子加速器
It's a particle accelerator...
希望能够将亚原子粒子对撞
hopefully capable of slamming subatomic particles together...
来重现大爆炸后一秒钟之内
to replicate the energies that existed...
所存在的能量
less than a second after the Big Bang.
大型强子对撞机将能够射出粒子
The Large Hadron Collider is going to be able to shoot particles...
彼此飞快对撞
very fast at each other...
瞬间
and for an instant...
将大量的质量集中在极小的空间里
there will be a lot of mass in a tiny little bit of space.
它有可能成功地释放出迷你黑洞
And it may actually succeed in popping off little mini black holes.
这是个惊人的想法
It's an amazing idea.
我们已接近于能够在实验室里制造出
We're on the verge of being able to make...
人造迷你黑洞
artificial tiny black holes in the laboratory.
如果大型强子对撞机
If the Large Hadron Collider...
真的造出了迷你黑洞
really does produce miniature black holes...
那将是非常激动人心的
it will also be really exciting...
因为那将表明迷你黑洞
because it will show that miniature black holes...
确实存在或可以存在
really do exist or can exist...
而不是理论上的凭空虚构
and are not just a figment of the theoretical imagination.
大型强子对撞机
The mini black holes...
可能制造出的迷你黑洞
that the Large Hadron Collider may produce...
将持续片刻才会消失
will last an instant before disappearing.
假如成功 实验还有可能揭示宇宙间
And, if successful, the experiment may also reveal secrets...
另一个费解的现象:
about another puzzling phenomenon in the universe:
根本看不见的物质
a matter that's completely invisible.
为了找到这个幽灵般的物质 科学家无须将眼光
To find this phantom matter, scientists had to look no further...
超出我们自己的星系街坊 银河系
than our own galactic neighborhood, the Milky Way.
怪异也许显而易见 行星 恒星 卫星 星系
Strange as it may seem, planets, stars, moons, and galaxies...
占到了宇宙全部物质的不足二成
make up less than 20 percent of all matter in the universe.
其余部分被暗物质所占有
The rest is made up of dark matter...
一种我们无法看见的物质 但是却无所不在
a form of matter we can't see, but exists everywhere.
暗物质是1930年代首次提出来的
Dark matter was first inferred in the early 1930s...
但是当时鲜有科学家认可这个概念
but very few scientists bought the concept at the time.
但是在过去二十年里
But in the past two decades...
这种看不见的现象的证据
the evidence for this invisible phenomenon...
已经势不可挡
has become overwhelming.
随着人们开始绘制银河系
As people began to map the Milky Way galaxy...
他们注意到其边缘的恒星
they noticed that the stars at the very edge...
移动非常之快 它们应该要飞出星系了
were moving so fast, they should have actually flown off the galaxy...
但是并没有
but they're not.
它们被某种东西羁留在一起
They're being held together by something invisible...
某种东西对星系施加着更大的吸引力
something that's adding more attractive force to the galaxy...
更大的引力
more gravity.
但是我们不知道那是什么
But we have no idea what this could be.
很奇怪 好大部分宇宙我们居然看不见
It's kind of strange that a lot of the universe we can't even see.
我们发觉暗物质是因为它与
We detect dark matter because it interacts gravitationally...
我们看得见的物质的引力互动
with mass that we do see.
星系旋转速度超过了
Galaxies spin faster than they should...
你所见到的物质
counting up the amount of gravity that you can see...
所具有的引力总量
from the matter they have.
如果那个引力不存在
And if that gravitational attraction weren't there...
高温气体将会消散
the hot gas would disperse.
因此我们知道引力超出了
So we know there's more gravity than we can account for...
我们所见到的物质总量
by the mass that we see...
那就被简单称为暗物质
and that is just simply called dark matter.
测量暗物质的一个方法是观察热X射线源气体
One method to measure dark matter is to look at hot X-ray-emitting gas...
以及它是如何被其中的引力控制住的
and how it's contained by the gravity present in it.
另一个观察事物的方法叫做引力透镜
Another way is to look at something called gravitational lensing.
引力透镜产生在我们观察非常遥远的星系
Gravitational lensing is caused when we see a very distant galaxy...
前面有一个前景星系时
behind a foreground galaxy...
远处星系所发出的光在经过较近的星系时
and the light from the distant one is bent...
会发生弯曲
as it goes around the nearer galaxy.
那好像是一个奇怪的想法 光确实会被透镜弯曲
That's kind of an odd idea-- light actually bending in a lens...
那实际上是空间本身形成的
that's really just formed by space itself.
引力扭曲了空间
Gravity makes that distortion in space.
因此我们注意到了
So we noticed there were...
引力扭曲了我们所看到的星系
these gravitationally distorted galaxies that we could see.
在我们估计其中心造成这种扭曲的质量时
And when we estimated what the mass in the center should have been...
发现它十分巨大
to make those distortions, it was gigantic...
超出了我们所见到质量的10倍
ten times more than the mass we saw there.
所以我们观察到了暗物质的集群
So we were observing a collection of dark matter.
暗物质可能构成了太空物质的大部分
Dark matter may constitute most of the mass in space...
但是宇宙间的多半能量
but the majority of energy in the universe...
来自另一种无形的现象叫做暗能量
comes from yet another invisible phenomenon called dark energy.
它是一种理论上的无处不在的能量形式
It's a theoretical form of energy that exists everywhere...
占到了宇宙全部质量与能量的70%
and accounts for 70 percent of all mass and energy in the universe.
或许最怪异的东西
Probably the weirdest thing...
宇宙间了解最少的东西
being that it's the least understood thing in the universe...
就是所谓的能量这个玩艺
is the stuff called dark energy.
暗能量 比方说
Dark energy, for example...
实际上与暗物质没有多大的关系
doesn't really have all that much to do with dark matter.
它们不是一回事
They're different things.
所谓的"暗"其实是指 我们只是不知道是怎么回事
The "dark" really means we just don't know what's going on.
暗能量首次发现是在1988年
Dark energy was first observed in 1998...
当时测量遥远恒星爆发
when measurements of faraway exploding stars...
被用来确定星系的距离
were used to determine the distances of galaxies.
发现那些星系的远离超过了预计
Those galaxies were found to be farther away than expected...
当时预计在宇宙间 它会随着时间减缓速度
in a universe that's slowing down with time.
天文学家于是得出结论
The astronomers thus concluded...
宇宙实际上随着时间膨胀愈发加快
that the universe is actually expanding more quickly with time...
暗能量可能是罪魁祸首
and dark energy may be the culprit.
宇宙充满了这种可恶的暗物质
The universe is filled with this repulsive dark energy.
它确实是怪异的东西
It's really weird stuff...
造成了宇宙的膨胀
that's causing the expansion of the universe...
随着时间而加速 加快
to speed up with time, to accelerate...
因此它呼的一下子 就这样 越来越快
so it's going whoosh, like that, you know, faster and faster.
发现它时真的感到很奇怪 知道吗?
And that was really weird when it was found, you know?
并不是预计的那样
It was not anticipated.
它至少在现在向我们表明了
It appears, at least to us at this time...
宇宙的更多部分是暗能量构成的
that even more of the universe is made up of dark energy...
那是某些物质
which is some substance.
它是黑暗的 不发光 我们看不到它
it's dark, it doesn't shine, we can't see it...
但是其活动加速了宇宙的膨胀
but it acts to speed up the expansion of the universe.
它是某种反引力
It's sort of an anti-gravity.
普通物质和能量趋向于减缓
Normal matter and energy tend to slow down the rate...
物体相互之间分开的速度
at which things are going away from each other...
因为普通物质彼此之间有引力的吸引
because normal things pull on one another gravitationally.
但是暗能量表现出
But dark energy appears to accelerate the rate...
加快物体彼此之间拉开的速度
at which objects pull away from each other.
有一个理论认为暗能量
One theory suggests that dark energy...
将会加速空间的膨胀到这样一个程度
will accelerate the expansion of space to such an extent...
整个宇宙将在500亿年里
that the entire universe will be ripped to shreds...
被扯成碎片
in about 50 billion years.
如果是那种情形 那么最终
If that's the case, then eventually...
不仅仅星系团会被相互扯开
not only will clusters of galaxies be ripped apart from one another...
而且星系本身也会被扯碎
and then galaxies themselves will get ripped apart...
恒星相互之间快速远离
as the stars zip away from one another.
于是太阳系
And then solar systems...
行星系也将被扯碎
planetary systems will get ripped apart.
于是接下来 甚至行星都将被扯碎
And then, later on, even planets will get ripped apart...
人类也将撕得粉身碎骨
and humans will get ripped apart.
最终 甚至原子和亚原子粒子都将被撕得粉碎
And finally, even atoms and subatomic particles will get ripped apart.
宇宙充满了千奇百怪的东西
The universe is full of odd and interesting things...
但是宇宙间最怪异的东西
but the most peculiar thing in the universe...
有可能就在我们的后院
may exist in our own backyard.
毫无疑问 最怪异的东西
By far and away the strangest thing...
在我看来 在宇宙间就是地球
in my opinion, in the universe is Earth...
我生于斯 长于斯 我了解其一二
and I live here, and I know something about it.
这真是个怪异之地
What a crazy place this is.
岩质行星 靠近恒星 布满绿色
A rocky planet, near a star with all this green stuff...
获取阳光 变成食物
that takes sunlight and turns it into food.
多怪异啊 但是 知道吗 对别人来说
That's strange but, you know, to others...
一点都没有什么特别之处 因为它是家园
there's nothing particularly peculiar because it's home.
我说啊 外太空里最怪异的东西就是人类
I'd say the strangest things in outer space are human beings.
我们确实不同凡响
We're definitely unusual...
迄今为止 我们在宇宙间还没有发现
and we haven't found any other beings like us yet...
有任何其它东西如我们这样
in the universe.
尽管那并不是说它们不存在
Although that's not to say that they aren't out there...
但是我们非常怪异
but we're pretty strange.